Annette Kar Baxter Papers, 1905-1984
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- SERIES III. WRITINGS 1963-88
  - Unpublished materials
    - Reviews of others' works
      - Identified, 1965-79, undated, [see also Contributions to books-Foreword, To Feed Their Hopes] (Box 25, Folder 4-7)
      - Unidentified, 1972-83 (Box 25, Folder 8-10)
    - Marginalia, undated (Box 26)
- SERIES IV. SPEECHES 1958-82
  - Speeches, 1958-82, undated (Box 27-28)
  - Notes, talks never given, etc. (Box 27-28, Folder 10-12)
  - Declined invitations, 1969-80 (Box 27-28, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1962-82, undated (Box 27-28, Folder 14)
- SERIES V. BARNARD COLLEGE 1952-84
  - Advisory Vocational Committee, 1969-70 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Alumnae Magazine Editorial Board, 1973-79, undated, [see also SERIES III-WRITINGS--Articles] (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - American Studies
    - Department business, 1963-84 (Box 29, Folder 3-20)
    - Requirements for the major, 1960-68, undated (Box 29, Folder 21)
    - Program revisions, suggestions, etc., undated (Box 29, Folder 22)
    - Unpublished reports, 1952-57 (Box 29, Folder 23)
    - Majors exam, 1954-56 (Box 29, Folder 24)
    - Classes, [see also History-Classes]
      - American Studies 1-2 (Box 29)
        - 1961-66 (Box 29, Folder 25-30)
        - 1967-83 (Box 30, Folder 1-20)
      - American Studies 3-4 (Box 30, Folder 21-34)
      - American Studies 5-6 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Requests for information about program, 1961-83, undated (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Syllabi from non-Barnard institutions, 1969, undated (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Position searches at other institutions, 1972-81, undated (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous, 1955-56, undated (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Appointments and salaries
    - General, 1954-83, undated (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Promotions, 1960-80, [see also OVERSIZE MATERIALS] (Box 31, Folder 7-12)
  - Archives, 1970-83, [see also History; SERIES VI. OTHER PROFESSIONAL ORGANIZATIONS-American Association of University Women] (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Barnard Bulletin, [see OVERSIZE MATERIALS] (Box 31)
  - Board of Trustees, 1972-83, undated (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Class of 1962, 1957-72, undated, [see also SERIES IV. SPEECHES] (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Coeducation, [see Columbia University-Relationship between Barnard and Columbia; SERIES VII. SUBJECT FILES--Education] (Box 31)
  - Columbia University
    - General, 1969-83 (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - American Culture Studies, 1982-83 (Box 31, Folder 17-18)
    - Columbia Spectator, [see OVERSIZE MATERIALS] (Box 31)
    - Executive Committee of the Faculty of Columbia, 1968 (Box 31, Folder 19)
    - Faculty Affairs Committee, 1970-71, [see also History-Tenure and promotion-closed until 2032; OVERSIZE MATERIALS] (Box 32, Folder 1-4)
    - Historiography lecture, 1972 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Information and Visitor Services, 1983 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Oral History
      - Advisory Committee, 1977-83, undated (Box 33, Folder 3)
      - Women's History Conference, 1982-83, undated (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Relationship between Barnard and Columbia, 1964-82, undated, [see also History; SERIES IV. SPEECHES; OVERSIZE MATERIALS] (Box 33, Folder 5-6)
    - Status of women, 1970-71, undated (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Summer Institute on Women, 1971 (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - University Committee for a Relevant Education, 1968 (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - University Seminar
      - Advisory Council, 1980-83 (Box 33, Folder 10)
      - American Civilization
        - 1953-57 (Box 33, Folder 11-12)
        - 1958-81 (Box 34, Folder 1-4)
      - Women and Society
        - 1974-76 (Box 34, Folder 5-6)
        - 1977-83, undated (Box 35, Folder 1-8)
      - Miscellaneous, 1966-79 (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Women's Affirmative Action Coalition, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Committees: General, 1961-82, undated (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Committee on Instruction, 1965-80, undated, [see also History, American Studies, Women's Studies] (Box 36, Folder 2-5)
  - Committee on the City: Danforth Foundation Report, 1968, undated (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Committee on Honors, 1980-82, [see also History, American Studies] (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Council on Development, 1968-73 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Course Guide, 1970-71 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Dean of Faculty search, 1977 (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Deanship Committee, 1970 (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Department chair notices, 1974-83, undated (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Development Committee, 1968-79 (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - Dissertation defense notices, 1970-74 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Dissertation defense questions and notes, undated (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Education program: student teachers, 1966-72 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Experimental College, 1978-80, undated (Box 37, Folder 4-5)
  - Experimental Studies Program, 1980-83, undated (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Faculty and officers of instruction notices, 1960-83, undated (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Faculty Appeal Board, 1962, undated (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Faculty Code, 1972-79 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Faculty Executive Committee, 1983 (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Faculty Research and Travel Committee, 1969 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Faculty-Trustee relationship, 1975 (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Freshman advising, 1966-67 (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - Freshman orientation, 1963-83, undated (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - Freshman seminar, 1981-83, undated (Box 37, Folder 15)
  - Greek life, 1983 (Box 37, Folder 16)
  - Health and Society Committee, [see Milbank Program for Health and Society] (Box 37)
  - History Department
    - Business (Box 37)
      - General (Box 37)
        - 1961-71 (Box 37, Folder 17-22)
        - 1972-84, undated (Box 38, Folder 1-15)
      - Confidential departmental business (Box 39, Folder 1-6)
        [Closed until 2012]
      - Department by-laws, 1973-83 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Columbia's history department, [see also Columbia--Relationship between Barnard and Columbia]
      - Correspondence, 1957-83 (Box 40, Folder 2)
      - Consultation agreements, 1973-77 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence with Dean of Faculty, 1970-83 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Former students teaching in history, undated (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - History Club, 1964, undated (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Planning survey, 1976-77 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - Classes
      - History 41-42, 1965-67, undated (Box 40, Folder 8-10)
      - History 61-62, 1967-68, undated (Box 40, Folder 11-12)
      - History 71-72, 1962-67, undated (Box 40, Folder 13-17)
      - History 73, 1970-71, undated (Box 40, Folder 18-19)
      - History 74, 1968-71, undated (Box 40, Folder 20-24)
      - History 78, 1971, undated (Box 41, Folder 1-2)
      - History 81-82, 1971-83, undated (Box 41, Folder 3-17)
      - History 83, 1967-69 (Box 41, Folder 18-20)
      - History 93-94, 1969 (Box 41, Folder 21)
      - History 99, 1975-82 (Box 41, Folder 22-25)
    - Potential class: Women's Lives, 1983 (Box 41, Folder 26)
      - Women in America (work in progress), [see also Classes] (Box 42, Folder 1-14)
    - Syllabi
      - Requests for Women in America, 1966-77 (Box 42, Folder 15)
      - American history and related syllabi from colleagues, 1948-83 (Box 42, Folder 16)
    - Tenure and promotion, [see also Faculty Affairs Committee] (Box 43-46)
      [Closed until 2032; a few files closed until 2057]
  - Housing, 1969 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Library, [see Wollman Library] (Box 47)
  - Medieval and Renaissance Studies, 1971-82 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Milbank Program for Health and Society, 1974-83 (Box 47, Folder 3-6)
  - Millicent Carey McIntosh Center Dedication Committee, 1968-69 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Newsletter, 1980-83 (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Office of the Registrar, 1968-83, undated (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Personnel Committee, 1983 (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - Public relations, 1962-83 (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - Reunion, 1963-82 (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - Search Committee for Interim President, 1975,1980 (Box 47, Folder 13-14)
  - Search for President: Baxter nominations, 1975, 1979-8 (Box 47, Folder 15-16)
  - Self-Study, 1979 (Box 47, Folder 17)
  - Senior class, 1977-83 (Box 47, Folder 18)
  - Seven College Conference, 1965-81 (Box 47, Folder 19)
  - Seventy-fifth Anniversary Year, 1961-63, [see also SERIES III. WRITINGS-"Women in Politics" exhibit] (Box 47, Folder 20)
  - Student papers (graded), 1969-82 (Box 47a, Folder 1-8)
  - Student protests, 1968-72 (Box 47a, Folder 9)
  - Student recommendations, 1960-83 (Box 47a, Folder 10)
  - Tenure procedures, 1971-83, undated (Box 47a, Folder 11)
  - Third Year Review, 1982 (Box 47a, Folder 12)
  - Thursday Noon Committee, 1961-66 (Box 47a, Folder 13)
  - Wollman Library, 1963-83, undated (Box 47a, Folder 14)
  - Women's Center
    - General, 1969-74, undated (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Creation, 1970-71 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Charter Committee, 1972-73 (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Institute for Advanced Study of Women in Society, 1977-79 (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Task Force on Women, 1982-83 (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Annual Report, 1972-82 (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Executive Committee, 1971-83, undated (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - Women's archives and library, 1970-82 (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - Search Committee for Director, 1971-72, 1983 (Box 48, Folder 9-10)
    - Brochures, 1971, [see also OVERSIZE MATERIALS] (Box 48, Folder 11)
    - Conferences and events, 1970-83, undated (Box 48, Folder 12)
    - Projects, 1972-83, undated (Box 48, Folder 13-15)
  - Women's Studies
    - Major, 1971-77 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Classes, 1970-83 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Bibliographies and reading lists, 1971-81 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - "Women's Studies at Barnard," 1970-82, undated (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Study Committee, 1970-75, undated (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - Women's Studies Review Committee, 1974, undated (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - Committee on Women's Studies, 1977-83 (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - Feminist Scholars Seminar, 1973, undated (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - Women's Studies at other institutions, 1970-81, undated (Box 49, Folder 9)
    - Requests for women's studies syllabi, 1970-83 (Box 49, Folder 10)
    - Position searches at other institutions, 1972-74, undated (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous, 1967-82, undated (Box 49, Folder 12)
- SERIES VI. OTHER PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES 1943-84
  - Fellowships and grants
    - American Association of University Women, 1972-73 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - American Council of Learned Societies, 1975-78 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Ford Foundation, Faculty Fellowships for Research on the Role of Women in Society, 1972-75, undated (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1975-76 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities, 1975-79, undated (Box 50, Folder 5-6)
    - Princeton University, Davis Center for Historical Studies, 1971-72 (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Radcliffe Institute, 1977 (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Rockefeller Foundation Humanities Fellowships, 1973-77, undated (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - Social Science Research Council, 1971-75 (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - Job opportunities
    - Bowdoin College, 1977 (Box 50, Folder 11)
    - City University of New York, 1974, undated (Box 50, Folder 12)
    - Manhattanville College, 1973-74 (Box 50, Folder 13)
    - Princeton University, 1980, undated (Box 50, Folder 14)
    - Sarah Lawrence College, 1965 (Box 50, Folder 15)
    - Trinity College, 1981-83 (Box 50, Folder 16)
    - Wellesley College, 1978-80 (Box 50, Folder 17)
    - Declined offers, 1971-81 (Box 50, Folder 18)
  - Organizations and conferences, [see also OVERSIZE MATERIALS]
    - American Association of University Women, [see also SERIES III. WRITINGS-Unpublished-Monographs] (Box 50)
      - Archives, 1965-74, undated (Box 51, Folder 1-3)
      - Articles, 1943-79, undated (Box 51, Folder 4)
      - Conferences and forums, 1970-78, undated (Box 51, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence, 1974-79 (Box 51, Folder 6)
      - Education Foundation, 1964-78, undated (Box 51, Folder 7)
      - Membership, 1963-82 (Box 51, Folder 8)
      - Newspapers, [see OVERSIZE MATERIALS] (Box 51)
      - Pamphlets, 1956-79 (Box 51, Folder 9)
    - American Heritage Foundation, 1947-49 (Box 51, Folder 10-12)
    - American Historical Association
      - Committee on Congressional Fellowships, 1980-82 (Box 51, Folder 13)
      - Correspondence, 1970-80, undated (Box 51, Folder 14)
      - Directory of Affiliated Societies, 1977 (Box 51, Folder 15)
      - Panel proposal, 1979 [did not take place] (Box 51, Folder 16)
    - American Medical Women's Association
      - General, undated (Box 51, Folder 17)
      - Women's Medical Association of New York City, 1983 (Box 51, Folder 18)
    - American National Heritage Association, 1974, undated (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - American Quarterly Editorial Board, 1976-82, [see also SERIES III. WRITINGS] (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - American Studies Association
      - General, 1963-83, undated (Box 52, Folder 3)
      - Metropolitan New York branch, 1964-83 (Box 52, Folder 4)
      - Panel proposal, 1982-83 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - American Woman's Association, 1948-81, undated (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - Another Mother for Peace, circa 1970 (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - ARARAT, 1961-77, [see also SERIES III. WRITINGS] (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - Armenian General Benevolent Union, Inc. (AGBU), 1965, undated, [see also SERIES VII. SUBJECT FILES-Armenian Assembly of America] (Box 52, Folder 9)
    - Arno Press, Inc., 1973-77, undated, [see also SERIES III. WRITINGS] (Box 52, Folder 10)
    - Brown University, 1951-52 (Box 52, Folder 11)
    - Bryn Mawr, M. Carey Thomas project, 1979-80 (Box 52, Folder 12)
    - Celebrate Women festival, 1972 (Box 52, Folder 13)
    - Children's Television Workshop, 1975 (Box 52, Folder 14)
    - Columbia Forum, 1961-74, [see also SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE-Friends and associates--Wensberg, Erik] (Box 52, Folder 15)
    - Compton Advertising Awards, 1981-83, undated (Box 52, Folder 16)
    - Compton Digest, 1982, undated (Box 52, Folder 17)
    - Conference in Theology for College and University Faculty, 1962-68 (Box 53, Folder 1-8)
    - Coordinating Committee on Women in the Historical Profession, 1974-84, undated (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - Coro Foundation, 1974-83 (Box 53, Folder 10)
    - Cosmopolitan Club
      - Correspondence, 1973-83 (Box 53, Folder 11)
      - Monthly bulletin, 1973-83 (Box 53, Folder 12)
      - Stim Committee, 1980-81, undated (Box 53, Folder 13)
      - Miscellaneous, 1978, undated (Box 53, Folder 14)
    - Council for International Exchange of Scholars, 1974-82 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Danforth Foundation, 1967 (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - Encampment for Citizenship, Inc., "Freedom & Angelina," 1978 (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Ford Foundation, Faculty Research Fellowship Program on Women in Society, 1973-75, [see also Fellowships and grants] (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Girl Scouts of the U.S.A., 1974 (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Holmes & Meier Publishers, Inc., 1983 (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - Intellectual History Group, 1979-83 (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - Institute for Women, 1972 (Box 54, Folder 8)
    - John Simon Guggenheim Foundation, 1972, [see also Fellowships and grants] (Box 54, Folder 9)
    - Kirkland College
      - Board of Trustees (Box 54)
        - General, 1970-75 (Box 54, Folder 10-12)
        - Science curriculum, 1973 (Box 54, Folder 13)
      - Correspondence, 1969-78, [see also SERIES II-CORRESPONDENCE--Friends and associates-- Babbitt, Nell; McIntosh, Millicent] (Box 54, Folder 14-15)
      - Merger with Hamilton, 1977-81 (Box 54, Folder 16)
      - Proposal, Conference on the Gifted Woman at the Threshold, 1974 (Box 54, Folder 17)
    - Ladies Home Journal, 1978, [see also Women in the Workforce Conference] (Box 54, Folder 18)
    - Lotos Club, 1981-83, undated (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Marcus Weiner Publishing, Inc., 1983 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Marymount Manhattan College, 1982 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Middlesex School
      - Anvil Association, 1979-83 (Box 55, Folder 4)
      - Board of Trustees, 1982-83 (Box 55, Folder 5)
      - Coeducation Committee, 1982-83 (Box 55, Folder 6-7)
      - Donation of library materials, 1982-83 (Box 55, Folder 8)
      - Miscellaneous, 1982-83 (Box 55, Folder 9)
    - Mister Rogers' Neighborhood, 1975 (Box 55, Folder 10)
    - Modern Language Association, 1971-72 (Box 55, Folder 11)
    - National Advertising Review Board, 1974-75, undated (Box 55, Folder 12)
    - National Association for Armenian Studies and Research, 1964-65, undated (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - National Council of Women
      - American Bicentennial Monthly, 1974-76 (Box 56, Folder 2)
      - Board of Directors, 1975 (Box 56, Folder 3)
      - Bulletin, 1965-83 (Box 56, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence, 1968-82 (Box 56, Folder 5)
      - Miscellaneous, 1965-83 (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities, consultation, [see also Fellowships and grants]
      - General, 1975-78, undated (Box 56, Folder 7)
      - Kaledin proposal, 1982-83 (Box 56, Folder 8)
      - Media programs, 1974-79 (Box 56, Folder 9)
    - National Organization for Women, 1970-71, undated (Box 56, Folder 10)
    - New York Public Library
      - Night of One Hundred Dinners, 1983 (Box 56, Folder 11)
      - Schomburg, 1971 (Box 56, Folder 12)
    - Organization of American Historians, 1971-79 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Oxford University Press, 1979 (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Plenum Publishing, Encyclopedia of Women, 1973, undated (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - Political Science Quarterly, 1980-82 (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - Princeton Club of New York, 1980-81, undated (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - Ramapo College, 1975-82 (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - "Remember the Ladies" exhibit, 1977 (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - Schlesinger Library, 1967-70 (Box 57, Folder 8)
    - Smith College Library, Council of Friends, 1967-69, undated, [see also SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL INFORMATION-Education--Smith] (Box 57, Folder 9)
    - Union for Experimenting Colleges and Universities, 1981-83, undated (Box 57, Folder 10)
    - Union Graduate School, 1981-83 (Box 57, Folder 11)
    - United Hospital Fund of New York, 1979-82 (Box 57, Folder 12)
    - USIA Consultation, evaluation of contemporary America seminar, 1972 (Box 57, Folder 13)
    - Virginia Gildersleeve International Fund for University Women, Inc., 1978-79, undated (Box 57, Folder 14)
    - Woman's Life, 1981-82 (Box 57, Folder 15)
    - Women in the Workforce Conference, 1980 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Women's Forum, 1981-83, undated (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - Women's History Research Center, 1971-73, undated (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - Women's Interart Center, Inc., 1981, undated (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - Women's International League for Peace and Freedom, conference: Violence in Our Time, 1968 (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - Women's Medical Association of New York City, [see American Women's Medical Association] (Box 58)
    - Women's Studies: An Inter-Disciplinary Journal, 1971-73, undated (Box 58, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous conferences, 1976-78 (Box 58, Folder 7)
  - Requests for consultation, 1970-78 (Box 58, Folder 8)
- SERIES VII. SUBJECT FILES 1905-83
  - American studies/history, [see also OVERSIZE MATERIALS] (Box 58)
    - Articles (Box 58)
      - American history, 1964-75, undated (Box 59, Folder 1)
      - American studies, 1958-80, undated (Box 59, Folder 2)
      - "Articles in American Studies", [see SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL INFORMATION-Family--James Baxter-Writings] (Box 59)
    - Bibliographies, 1950, undated (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - Conference announcements
      - American history, 1975-83, undated (Box 59, Folder 4)
      - American studies, 1971-82, undated (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - Journal offers
      - American history, undated (Box 59, Folder 6)
      - American studies, 1960-83, undated (Box 59, Folder 7)
    - Newsletters, 1961-74 (Box 59, Folder 8)
    - Programs
      - American history, 1966-76, undated (Box 59, Folder 9)
      - American studies, 1967-80 (Box 59, Folder 10-11)
    - Publishers' notifications
      - A-L, 1962-83, undated (Box 59, Folder 12)
      - M-Z, 1971-83, undated, [see also OVERSIZE MATERIALS] (Box 60, Folder 1)
      - The Americanist, 1967 (Box 60, Folder 2)
      - Arno Press, 1968, undated (Box 60, Folder 3)
      - Austin Book Shop, undated (Box 60, Folder 4)
      - Dover, 1963, undated (Box 60, Folder 5)
  - Armenian Assembly of America, 1982-83 (Box 60, Folder 6)
  - Chopin, Kate, 1970-76 (Box 60, Folder 7)
  - Education, 1956-80, [see also Women-Education] (Box 60, Folder 8)
  - Equal Rights Amendment, 1952-83 (Box 60, Folder 9)
  - James, Henry, 1963-80 (Box 60, Folder 10)
  - Miller, Henry, 1961-70, undated (Box 60, Folder 11)
  - Revolution and protest, 1964-69, [see also Women] (Box 60, Folder 12)
  - Status of women (Box 60)
  - State and local reports
    - General, 1964-70 (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - New York, 1966-82 (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - United States
      - General, 1934-72 (Box 61, Folder 3)
      - Citizen's Advisory Council, 1964-70 (Box 61, Folder 4)
      - Colleges, 1934-74, undated (Box 61, Folder 5)
      - Department of Labor, 1938-67 (Box 62, Folder 1-2)
      - President's Committee on the Status of Women, 1961-63 (Box 62, Folder 3-4)
      - Public service, 1949 (Box 62, Folder 5)
      - State Department, 1972 (Box 62, Folder 6)
    - International
      - General, 1970, [see OVERSIZE MATERIALS] (Box 62)
      - International Council of Women newsletter, 1970 (Box 62, Folder 7)
      - International Women's Year, 1974 (Box 62, Folder 8)
      - United Nations
        - 1962-Jan 1965 (Box 62, Folder 9-10)
        - Feb 1965-75 (Box 63, Folder 1-2)
  - Women
    - Biographies, 1964-83, undated (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - Clubs, 1968-83 (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - Demonstrations and protests, 1969-70, undated (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - Education
      - Co-ed vs. single sex, 1948-83 (Box 63, Folder 6)
      - Higher education, 1961-74, undated (Box 63, Folder 7)
      - Women faculty, 1970-83, undated (Box 63, Folder 8)
    - Family, 1948, undated (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - Feminism/feminist movement, 1970-83, undated, [see also Women's liberation] (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - Occupations
      - General, 1964-83, undated (Box 64, Folder 3)
      - Housewives, 1976-80, undated (Box 64, Folder 4)
      - Medicine, 1944-75, undated (Box 64, Folder 5)
      - Ordination, 1972-75 (Box 64, Folder 6)
      - Prostitution, 1960-78, undated (Box 64, Folder 7)
      - Science, 1940-45, undated (Box 64, Folder 8)
    - Psychology, 1964-73, undated (Box 64, Folder 9)
    - Sex differences, 1967-81 (Box 64, Folder 10)
    - Sex roles, 1953-72, undated (Box 64, Folder 11)
    - Sexuality, 1967-69 (Box 64, Folder 12)
    - Stereotypes, 1970-78, undated (Box 64, Folder 13)
    - Suffrage, 1968-79 (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - Women's bodies, 1975, undated (Box 65, Folder 2)
    - Women's liberation, 1969-73, undated, [see also Feminism/feminist movement] (Box 65, Folder 3-4)
  - Women's history/women's studies, [see also OVERSIZE MATERIALS]
    - General, 1959-83, undated (Box 65, Folder 5)
    - Bibliographies, 1905-83, undated (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - Conferences, 1969-83, undated (Box 65, Folder 7)
    - Curriculum, 1975, undated (Box 65, Folder 8)
    - Journal offers, 1972-74, undated (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - Newsletters, 1970-80, undated (Box 66, Folder 2-3)
    - Programs, 1971-73 (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - Publisher's notifications and reading lists, 1966-83, undated (Box 67)
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS
  - Women's history/women's studies bibliography, undated (Box 68)
  - Biographical material: Episcopal New Yorker, 1968, 1971 (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - Writings
    - Advertisement, To Be a Woman in America, Times Books, Christmas, 1978 (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - Galleys
      - The Universal Self-Instructor, undated (Box 69, Folder 2)
      - "American Women from 1876 to the Present: The Search for Identity," n.d. (Box 69)